2007年的5月  你们的\n莉莉阿姨和马修叔叔结婚了
In May of 2007,\nAunt Lily and Uncle Marshall got married
在纽约北部著名的
at the historic Van Smoot\nHouse in upstate New York.
莉莉  这里真漂亮
Wow, it's beautiful, Lily.
跟我想象中的一样
Yeah. It's just how\nI always pictured it.
这纯粹是P话
Well, that was a load of crap.
孩子们  当你们结婚的时候\n你们也不得不面对
You see, kids, when you get married,\nyou learn a hard lesson.
你想象中的婚礼跟最后举行的那个相比\n几乎没有一点相似
The wedding you set out to have is\nalmost never the wedding you end up with.
我们决定举行\n一个小型户外婚礼
So, we've decided on a small,\noutdoor wedding,
只有家人和好朋友
just family and close friends.
人数会控制在25人左右
No more than 25 people
在一个漂亮的花园
in a beautiful\ngarden somewhere,
也许会请吉他作伴奏
maybe an acoustic\nguitar playing
当我们走过礼堂的时候
while we walk down the aisle.
你们也许已经\n知道有人已经去过法院
And maybe you already know someone\nwho went down to the courthouse
而且已经注册成为了的主婚人
and registered as an officiant
这样他或是她
so that he or she-- he--
就可以主持婚礼
could perform the ceremony.
你讨厌婚姻 \n怎么想来主持这个婚礼
But you hate marriage.\nWhy do you want to perform the ceremony?
因为到时在座的每位女性\n脑海里都会植入这样一个场景
Because it subtly implants in\nthe mind of every woman there
当我问她们某个问题时
that when I ask a question,
她们会说   我'做'
you say, "I do."
距离婚礼越近
Yeah. The closer you get\n to the big day,
你就得做越多妥协
the more concessions you make.
这下好了  现在我妈\n又要求我邀请了莱斯尼尔一家子
Great. Now my mom's making\nme invite the Lessners.
这下总人数的\n已经是原来的三倍了
This puts our numbers\nin the triple digits.
我猜有的时候\n更少的人就意味着更多的...人
Wow. I guess sometimes,\nLessner is more... ner.
好比你知道\n有些时候少却意味着多
You know how like\nsometimes less is more.
你现在的行为\n就是一个很好的例子 亲爱的
Yeah. This is one of\nthose times, sweetie?
其实这也无谓\n就举行一个大点的户外婚礼好了
You know what? That's okay.\nIt'll be a slightly big outdoor wedding.
婚外无法在户外举行了
So it's not going to be an\noutdoor wedding anymore.
马修他爸不断强调\n如果我们在纽约举行户外婚礼
Marshall's dad is convinced if we\nhave an outdoor wedding in New York,
他会疯掉\n看来只能移到室内了
he's going to get mugged,\nso it's going to be inside now.
这样也不错\n我们仍然可以有吉他伴奏
It'll be great. We're still going\nto have our acoustic guitar player.
现在  吉他也没了
So now,\ninstead of an acoustic guitar,
取而代之的是竖琴
we're having a harp player.
我爸爸欠那个人的人情\n而他女儿会弹竖琴
Yeah. My dad owes a guy, and...\nthat guy's daughter plays the harp.
她辣吗?我很乐意\n从名单上删掉一个"竖琴演奏者"
Is she hot? I'd love to be able to\ncross "harp player" off my list.
你的名单有多长
How long is this list?
我从来不数名单有多少页
Dude, I'm not gonna count\nhow many pages the list is.
我又不是傻瓜
I'm not crass.
没关系  她是个孕妇
Well, it doesn't matter anyway.\nShe's pregnant.
太好了  我可以删掉两个了
Sweet! I can cross\noff two things.
终于到了莉莉和马修\n举行大型室内婚礼的日子
And the day arrives for Lily and\nMarshall's very big indoor wedding...
一个竖琴
with a harp.
你好 莉莉
Hi, Lily.
你真的大着肚子...
Wow. Andrea. You really are pregnant.
你挺个大肚子怎么弹琴?
Yeah. How do you play the harp\n with your belly so...?
我弹不了全部... \n我只能弹到一半的弦
Oh, I don't really--\nI can only reach about half the strings.
你只能弹半个竖琴?
You only play half the harp?
是的
Yeah.
莉莉 我来搞定这个
Oh, no. Uh, okay.\nLily, I will take care of this.
我负责弹另一半\n很难学吗?
Um, I'll just pluck the other half.\nIs it hard to learn?
我已经学了12年竖琴了
I've been studying\nthe harp for 12 years.
但我学东西很快
Yeah, but I'm a fast learner.
你知道"吉他英雄"?一天我就学会了\n(一款ps2音乐游戏)
You ever hear of "Guitar Hero"?\nLearned that in a day.
有"竖琴英雄"吗?
Is there a "Harp Hero"?
罗宾 不要紧
Robin, it's fine.
预产期是什么时候?
So, so, when are you due?
周二
Tuesday.
快了啊
Wow, that's soon.
上周二
Last Tuesday.
真是见鬼了\n我们不该让她来
Holy crap, we have to fire her.
她完全可能在\n你的婚礼中生个孩子出来
She's gonna drop a shorty in\nthe middle of your ceremony.
罗宾  我不会自乱阵脚的
Robin, I'm not going\nto freak myself out.
我讨厌那些女人总是说
I hate those women who say,
我婚礼一定得完美
"Oh, my wedding\nhas to be perfect."
天不从人愿 \n有时DJ会把音乐搞砸
Things go wrong. Sometimes the\ndeejay screws up your playlist.
有时你会在离开时摔倒在胎盘上
Sometimes you slip on placenta\nduring the recessional.
我能来杯scotch and soda? 要快\n(一种鸡尾酒)
Can I grab a scotch\nand soda real quick?
婚礼开始前不提供服务
No. I'm not allowed to serve\nanything until the reception.
你浪费了一个机会拿小费 兄弟
Wow. You just cost\nyourself a big tip, buddy.
我不能收小费 兄弟
I'm not allowed to\naccept tips, buddy.
能接受批评吗?
You allowed to\naccept criticism?
你...脑袋长在P股上 兄弟
You, sir, are an ass... buddy.
你们想知道竖琴师\n弹不响哪个弦吗?
Hey, you want to know what line\ndoesn't work on a harp player?
宝贝  用力
"Hey, baby, want to pluck?"
是吗?她到现在也还没生出来
Really? That didn't work.
一点都没有
Not even a little.
比尔是谁?
Hey! Who's Bill? Bill?
我在吧台看到这家伙
Yeah. This guy came\nup to me at the bar.
我能问你件事吗?
Can I ask you something?
如果仪式上有人抢婚怎么办?
Where in the ceremony is the place\nwhere they ask if anyone objects?
没有人还那样做
Uh... Don't think\nthey do that anymore.
那你觉得什么时候做才合适
Oh, so when do you think\nsomeone should do it?
是等仪式告一段落的时候还是?
Just wait for a lull or what?
他是不是看起来\n像个不伦不类的裁判?
Oh, no. Did he look like a guy who tried\n to be an umpire but failed?
有点像
He kind of did.
是斯古特?
That's Scooter.
你高中的男朋友 斯古特 ?
Your high school\nboyfriend, Scooter?
他真名叫比尔
His real name is Bill.
肯定我妈邀请他的
My mom must have invited him.
为什么?她为什么叫他啊?
Why? Why would she do that?
我们两家关系很好
Our families are really close.
但是我的前男友
But my ex-boyfriend?
用用脑子啊 老妈
Come on, Mom.
被爸发现和你好上的\n职业运动员我都没有邀请
I didn't invite that professional\nsquash player Dad busted you with.
我需要一杯酒
Oh, I need a glass of wine.
我去拿
I'll get it.
谢了 马修那边怎么样?
Oh, thanks.\nHey, how's Marshall doing?
挺好的
He's great.
正准备理发呢
He's about to get his hair cut.
我怕我表妹给他理的太短了
Oh. I'm worried my cousin's\ngoing to cut it too short.
我也是  我一晚上都在担心
Me, too. I was up all night.
你在这干嘛啊?
Hello, Lily. Hey, Bill. Hey, Barney. Scooter, what are\n you doing here?
不再是以前的"斯古特"
It's not "Scooter" anymore.
我现在是比尔
It's Bill.
我变了很多了 莉莉
A lot of things have\nchanged about me, Lily,
但是有一点没有变
but one hasn't.
我仍然爱你
I still love you.
我来这是想让你回到我身边
And I came here\nto win you back.
你真搞笑 不是真的吧
You're really cute.\nOh, no. Really?
莉莉 我知道这很疯狂
Lily, I-I know it's crazy,
但我爱你
but I love you,
假如你能看着我的眼睛
and if you can\nlook me in the eye
告诉我你想跟马修结婚
and tell me that you\nwant to marry Marshall,
我现在就走以后\n再也不踏足你生活半步
I will leave right now and\nbe out of your life forever.
我想...
I want...
我想要杯葡萄酒
Scooter! I need a glass of wine.
我想让你立刻从我眼前消失
And I need you to\nget out of my face.
这是新娘要的 所以...
It's for the bride, so...
白的还是红的?
White or red?
白的
White.
他还想要杯scotch and soda\n(巴尼之前要的酒)
And, uh...\nshe'd also like a scotch and soda.
马上就来
You got it.
她还想要一碗熏杏仁
She'd also like a bowl\nof smoked almonds.
我这没有
I don't have any,
不过我想我可以出去买点
but I guess I could run out\nto the corner and get some.
这是她一生中\n最重要的一天 所以...
Well, it's only the biggest\nday of her life, so...
好戏开始了
Let the games begin.
给你  我先走了\n好多"事"要做
Here. Can't stay.\nGot to try something.
也许我的话不能改变你的想法
Maybe my words won't\nchange your mind,
但也许这首诗会
but maybe the words\nof a poet will.
从"十一月的雨"上摘取的
I read from "November Rain."
W・阿里克斯 ・罗斯写的
By W. Axl Rose.
这歌不错
That is a good song.
巴尼说你需要把\n这个叫斯古特的赶出去?
Barney said you needed me to\nbounce some guy named Scooter?
比尔跑什么?
What's up with Bill?
他就是斯古特
That's Scooter.
我来搞定
I'm on it.
可以给我  你的电话号码吗?
- Hey. - Hey. Can I have your phone number?
不...
No.
新娘要的
It's for the bride.
等等  我去拿支笔
Oh. Hold on.\nLet me go get a pen.
新娘让你走慢点
The bride wants\nyou to walk slower.
罗宾
Oh, wow. Oh. Robin...
我的妆看起来太完美了
My makeup looks\nperfect right now,
我感动得都想哭了 \n快做点什么
and I'm about to cry.\nDo something.
我胸部上有胸毛
I have hairy nipples.
真的吗?
Really?
假的 但是效果很明显 不是吗?
No, but it worked, didn't it?
嗯 这招不错
Hey. Funny story.
我绊倒了一个人\n我以为他是斯古特
I tackled this guy I\nthought was Scooter.
后来发现原来是摄影师
Turns out it was\nyour photographer.
没关系 我手机可以摄像\n 所以一切都很顺利
Don't worry. I got this sweet\ncamera phone, so we're covered.
没有摄像师?
There's a photographer?
- 我的打电话给... \n- 罗宾 不用了
Oh, my God. - Okay, I just have to call...\n - Robin, stop. Stop.
没关系
It's okay.
今天我不会让\n任何事情来影响我的心情
I am not gonna let\nanything get to me today.
我刚才收到\n花店打过来的电话
I just got a call from the florist.\nThe flowers won't be here
花要到仪式举行\n一半以后才能送到
till halfway through\nthe ceremony.
我没事
I'm okay.
我不想打扰你 但是...\n我在停车场找到你的面纱了
I hate to bother you, but... I think\nI found your veil in the parking lot.
我没事
I'm fine.
告诉你件事: 我羊水破了
Just FYI: my water broke.
但是我应该可以
But I can probably...
挺过去
...make it through.
我很冷静
Totally cool.
莉莉 我想我没带\n你的婚用短裤
Oh, no. Lily, I think I forgot\n your bridal panties.
我以为我带了 对不起
I-I thought I had them.\nI'm so sorry.
没事 我就穿现在这条
Oh, it's okay,\nI'll just wear the ones I have on.
你确定?
Are you sure?
我今天就要嫁给马修了
I'm marrying Marshall today.
这些都不会影响我走过礼堂
So it doesn't even matter that\nI'm gonna walk down the aisle
屋里没有花\n我也没有面纱
without a veil in a room\nthat has no flowers
只有半个竖琴会响\n弹的人还马上就要生了
to the music of half a harp\nplayed by a woman who's crowning,
我高中男朋友还跑来\n朗诵'枪炮与玫瑰'的歌词
as my high school boyfriend\nreads Guns N' Roses lyrics.
无所谓
But that's okay,
反正也没有摄像师在拍
because there's no photographer there\nto take any pictures of it anyway.
莉莉 你还好吗?
Lily, are you okay?
你说呢?我当然不好了
What do you think?!\nOf course I'm not okay!
我的婚礼每件事\n有可能出错的事都出错了
Everything that could possibly\ngo wrong at my wedding has!
全都搞砸了
It's ruined!
你不是说"你不想要完美的婚礼"吗?
What happened to "I don't\nwant a perfect wedding"?
长大吧 罗宾!我当然\n想要完美的婚礼啊!
Oh, grow up, Robin!\nOf course I want a perfect wedding!
我只是不想过分关注婚礼 但是...
Oh, God. I wanted... I wanted not\nto care about the wedding, but...
我今天应该是像个公主一样
I do. I... I'm supposed to\nfeel like a princess today.
你是个公主
And you will.
一切都会好的 宝贝
It's gonna be okay, sweetie.
我们出去走走吧?我有东西能让你感觉好点
Why don't we go outside? I have\nsomething that'll make you feel better.
你能有什么让我感觉好点?
What could you have that could\npossibly make me feel better?
我希望马修今天过得比我好
God, I hope Marshall's having\na better day than I'm having.
- 天哪!\n- 怎么了
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God. - Oh, my God!\n - What?
是不短
Well, it's not too short.
我的头发!看看我的头发!\n她毁了我的发型!
My hair! Look at my hair!\nShe ruined my hair!
我看起来像一个后街男孩
I look like one of\nthe Backstreet Boys!
确实是
You totally do.
还不是好的后街男孩
And not even the good\nBackstreet Boys,
像老的那个 跳舞瘸腿 \n跑回来作指导的那个后街男孩子
the older, lame dance move,\ncomeback tour Backstreet Boys.
后街男孩有好的?
The good Backstreet Boys?
我该怎么办啊?!
Guys! Guys!\nWhat am I gonna do?!
到底发生什么了
What-what the hell\nhappened to you?
莉莉的表妹在美容学校学习
Lily's cousin is\nin beauty school,
莉莉不想让她给她做头发
and Lily didn't want\nher to do her hair,
她说让表妹给我做
so she said she could do mine.
只要别太短就行了 行吗?
So, um,\njust not-not too short, okay?
不会的 我们甚至都不要用到剪刀
Oh, no,\nwe don't even have to cut it at all.
只是搞搞造型
Could just give it some style.
听起来不错
Oh, okay, yeah, that's great.
因为 太短的话就会看起来傻傻的
'Cause, um, when it gets too short,\nit starts to look weird.
我不想剪完后看起来很傻
And I don't want to look weird\nwhen I'm up there, you know.
我给你弄个酷的造型吧
Ooh, I could give you\nsome cool guy tips.
我想我已经够酷了
I don't think I need\nadvice on how to be cool,
行 你弄吧
but yeah, great,\nlay that on me.
我不可能这样去结婚\n门都没有
I can't get married like this!\nThere's no way!
让我看看能做什么
Ah, let me see what I can do.
你能做什么啊?
What? What can you do?
我有超能力
I have a superpower.
莉莉会杀了我的
Lily is gonna kill me!
看看我!
Look at me!
她不会想跟这样的我结婚的
She's not gonna want\nto marry me like this.
不可能  她当然会跟你结婚的
That's crazy.\nOf course she will.
你愿意嫁给我吗?
Would you marry me?
不会 不是因为你的头发 \n我有个原则
No. But not because of the hair.\nIt's because I have a rule:
永远不要跟一个\n跟你比赛放屁的人结婚
never marry anyone you've\nhad a farting contest with.
你是说我不该跟莉莉结婚了?
Oh, great. So now you're saying Lily\nand I shouldn't even get married?
大家注意一下?
Could I have everyone's\nattention, please?
这是为了新娘
It's for the bride.
第一 新娘希望
One, the bride would...
大家先别紧张
like all of this tension\nout of my shoulders.
她希望
And she would like, let's say,
你...穿着不合时宜\n超短裙的那个 脱掉
you in the inappropriately\nshort dress to rub them.
第二条
Two...
第二条是什么来着?
What was two?
我们这儿发生了点情况
Okay, we have a\nbit of a situation.
别紧张
Let's not panic.
我们来找个解决办法
Let's just find a solution.
兄弟 你把你头剃了
Dude, you shaved\nyour freakin' head.
是啊 但是很好
Yeah, yeah, but it's good.
我应该剃光的 \n多好的办法啊!
I ought to shave it all off.\nWhat a great solution.
光头更酷 对吗?
Just be bald 'cause\nit's cool, right?
布鲁斯・威利斯 迈克尔・乔丹\n布兰妮・斯皮尔斯 都是...
Bruce Willis, Michael Jordan,\nBritney Spears...
噢天啊 我做了什么?!
Oh, God, what did I do?!
你怎么能让我把我头剃了啊?!
How could you let\nme shave my head?!
-什么?!\n-你是最糟的伴郎!
- What?!\n- You're the worst best man ever!
我恨你
I hate you!
我不出去!我走了再也不回来了
I'm not going out there!\nI'm leaving and I'm never coming back.
我要去找树边\n那个石头底下藏着的钱
I'm gonna go find that money\nunder the rock by the tree
我要去墨西哥城市和\n那里的兄弟们一起在海边生活
and go live with the guys on\nthe beach in Zihautanejo.
兄弟 住那得都是犯罪分子
Dude, those guys are criminals.
理德・安迪是无辜的
Only Red Andy was\nfalsely accused.
泰德 你是我的伴郎 做点什么
Ted, you're my best man!\nYou got to do something!
好 过来 深呼吸\n深呼吸 好点了吗?
Okay, all right, come here.\nJust breathe, breathe, all right?
别担心 别担心
Don't worry. Don't worry.
- 我把这个拿走\n- 不
- I'll just... I'll take these.\n- No!
- 你好 是本大叔吗?\n- 是的
- Uh, hi. Uncle Ben, right?\n- Yes.
我们 我们遇到点小问题
Yes, we're, we're having a little\nbit of a problem back there.
我想看看你能不能帮帮我们
Um, and I was wondering\nif you could help us out.
马修不小心剃光了一些头发
Yeah. Marshall accidentally\n shaved part of his head.
- 不是吧!\n- 就是这样的
- Oh, no!\n- Yeah.
我在想
Yeah, so here's what\nI was thinking.
如果我们能找点\n什么能盖住他剃光的部分
What if I found something\nto cover up the bald area?
这样可能有效
Yeah, that would probably work,
但是用什么呢?
but with what?
就是比较难
That's a tough one.
也许某种假发或者是...
Maybe a wig of some\nsort or a, um...
男士假发
toupee.
而且还得跟他头发颜色差不多
Something that matches\nhis hair color,
跟你头发颜色差不多
which is, which is kind of the same\ncolor as the top of your hair.
在座的有谁戴这种假发呢?
Mm, yeah. Does anyone here wear a toupee?
应该不难找
Shouldn't be hard to find out.
他们大部分戴\n的都难看得很明显
Most of them are pretty bad.
你说的太对了
That is true. That is true.
我们只需要找个戴着假发的
We just need to find\nsomeone who wears a toupee
假发颜色相同
that is the same color
跟马修或是跟你的头发颜色一样的
as Marshall's and your hair.
这就相当难了
Boy, that's a\npretty tall order.
真的吗?
Really?
你觉得这样放眼望去找不到吗？
You can't think of any\nplace in the general area
我给你说的那种假发
where there might be a toupee of\nthe kind I'm describing to you?
除非我头上...
No, not off the top of my...
不行
No. Can't.
这样吧 \n我包里有50美元
Let me come at this from a different\nangle. I got $50 in my pocket
- 可能有更多...\n- 新娘征用了
- which is probably a lot more...\n- The bride needs this.
事实上  我觉得挺有效
Actually, I think\nit kinda works.
的确
It totally does.
巴尼?
Barney?
老实说 我...
To be honest, I'm, uh,
我嫉妒你 我没有机会戴上它
I'm jealous I don't\nget to wear it.
好了 问题解决了
Okay, problem solved.
危机解除
Crisis averted.
准备结婚吧
Let's get me married.
看起来很烂 对吧?
It looks terrible, doesn't it?
看起来就像动物的皮
It kinda looks like fur,
看起来像刚洗干净的野人
which gives you the appearance\nof a cleaned-up Bigfoot.
- 你知道的\n- 刚才是客气的讲法
- Oh, you know...\n- In a bad way.
发型不错 兄弟
Hey. Cool hair, bro.
你衬衫呢?
What happened to your shirt?
我刚才撞倒服务生的时候\n把汤料弄在衣服上了
I got sauce on it when\nI tackled the caterer.
你要找件新的吗?
You gonna put another shirt on?
没事
No, I'm good.
你们看见斯古特吗?
Hey, you guys seen Scooter?
什么?斯古特在这?\n他怎么会在我婚礼上?
What? What? Scooter's here?\nThat guy's at my wedding?
不会太久的 兄弟
Not for long, bro.
不会太久
Not for long.
我得出去透透气
Okay, you know what?\nI need some air.
那我们就出去走走吧 怎么样?
I think we should go\nfor a walk, okay?
这个会把所有的问题都盖掉
It would cover up the problem.
又很喜庆
It's festive
它代表了这个国家的伟大传统
and it celebrates the heritage\nof this great nation.
你车上如果有这个再说吧
Okay, unless you actually\nhave one in your car,
不要再叫我用\n这个国家运动员头巾了
stop suggesting authentic\nNative American headdress.
哦  不
Oh, no.
哦 天哪!
Oh, my God!
马修...
Marshall...
莉莉 我们现在不该见面的
Lily, you're not\nsupposed to see me.
我觉得你不应该跟任何人类见面
Holy crap, I don't think\nanyone's supposed to see you.
怎么了?埃米弄得吗?
What happened?\nDid Amy do this to you?
她弄了个烂造型\n其它的我弄得 对不起 宝贝
Just the frosted tips.\nI did the rest. I'm sorry, baby.
我搞砸了整个婚礼
I've ruined the whole wedding,\nhaven't I?
不 你没有 亲爱的
Oh, no,\nyou didn't ruin the wedding, sweetie.
它已经被搞砸了
It was already ruined.
没有花  没有摄影师
There's no flowers,\nno photographer.
另外斯古特还在这
Oh, and Scooter's here,\nby the way.
我知道 我听说了
Yeah, I know. I heard.
我面纱弄脏了 \n弹竖琴的就要生了
My veil got thrashed,\nthe harp player is in labor,
我还没有穿婚用短裤
and I'm not wearing\nmy wedding underwear.
什么?那你内裤背后\n没有"属于马修"了?
What? No "Property of\nMarshall" across the back?
那大家怎么知道\n这个P股是谁的
How are people going to\nknow whose butt that is?
到底怎么了?
What happened?
记得我们希望的婚礼吗?\n亲密的户外婚礼?
Remember the wedding we wanted,\nthe intimate outdoor ceremony?
我希望我们能有那样的婚礼
I wish we could\nhave that wedding.
那就做吧
So do it.
什么?
What?
现在就结
Get married now.
就在这
Right here.
这不就是你们想要的户外
Look, it's outside like\nyou always wanted.
有亲密的朋友
Intimate, close friends.
没有吉它\n但是已经很像了
There's no guitar,\nbut it's pretty close.
巴尼可以当证婚人
Barney can officiate.
是的 我可以
Yes. Yes, I can.
不好意思\n你们都掉了点东西
Uh, excuse me, guys.\nYou all dropped something:
下巴掉啦
your jaws--
现在要来主持婚礼啦
because Barney Stinson is about\nto aid and abet a marriage.
这样可以吗?我的意思是\n那里面人怎么办啊?
Could we even do that? I mean,\nwhat about all those people in there?
里面也结啊 到时候\n即使里面搞砸了
Do that one, too.\nAnd then when everything goes wrong,
你们也不会在意的\n因为真正的婚礼你已经举行过了
you won't care because you already\nhad the real wedding out here.
你觉得怎么样 宝贝?
What do you think, baby?
我喜欢
I love it.
我也是
Me, too.
那我们开始吧 \n让我们在结婚前结婚吧
Let's do it.\nLet's get married before we get married.
等等 等等
Great. Wait, hold on.
打扰一下 先生\n我们能借借你的帽子吗?
Excuse me, sir. Could we borrow your hat?
- 当然\n- 谢谢你!
Okay. Thank you.
帽子!我们连美国头巾都想到了\n却没想到帽子
Hat. We thought of authentic before we thought of hat.\n Native American headdress
欢迎光临!
Thank you all for coming.
对于那些不认识我的人来说
For those of you\nwho don't know me...
我并不是很相信婚姻
I'm not the biggest\nbeliever in marriage.
但是你们两个太般配了
But... you two are so great together,\nyou know?
你们就像是为\n对方量身定做的一样
It's like you were, uh,\nmade for each other.
- 他要哭了 \n- 我没有 我没有
- He's gonna cry. - No, I'm not. I'm not, I'm not, I'm not,\n  I'm not, I'm not.
莉莉  马修
Lily and Marshall...
当人们看到你们的时候\n他们看到了真爱
when everyone sees you, they...
这是世界上最好的爱
see true love. It's the best love...
我们能不能直接跳到...\n交换戒指部分去
Can we just, um,\nmove on to the rings or something?
- 我没带我的宣拆稿 \n- 我也没带
Oh, no. I don't have my vows. I don't have mine either.
你们不需要那个 你们只要说你们为什么爱对方就好了
You don't need your vows.\nJust say why you love each other.
我先来
Okay, I'll go first.
莉莉 我爱你的理由有成千上万
Lily, there are a million\n reasons why I love you.
你让我笑 你在我\n生病的时候照顾我
You make me laugh and you take care of\n me when I'm sick.
你很窝心 很在乎我\n你甚至做了以我命名的菜
You're sweet, caring and you even\ncreated an egg dish and named it after me.
她做了这个还叫它鸡蛋马修  很棒
She puts a little Italian dressing in scrambled eggs before she cooks them. It's called "Eggs Marshall,"\n and it's awesome.
但我爱你最主要的原因是 \n你是我的至友
But the main reason that I love you is that you're my best friend, Lily.
你是我永远的最好的朋友
You're, uh... you're the best friend I ever had.
- 抱歉 伙计 \n- 没关系
- I'm sorry, buddy.\n- No problem.
没关系
It's totally okay.
到我了 谢谢
My turn.
我爱你 因为你很幽默 \n你让我感觉到被爱  你让我有安全感
Oh, thank you. Marshall, I love you because you're funny and you make me feel loved and you make me feel safe
在我们周年庆的时候你送我一件衬衫
and for our anniversary you\ngave me a sweatshirt that says,
上面写着 莉莉和马修从96年就在一起了
"Lily and Marshall.\nRockin' It Since '96."
我真希望我现在穿着它\n它闻起来有你的味道
I kinda wish I was wearing it right now 'cause it smells like you.
但我爱你最主要的原因是\n你 马修・埃斯尔森  你总是让我开心
But the main reason I love you, Marshall Ericksen, is you make me happy. You make me happy all the time.
- 我找到你的短裤了 \n- 用不着了
Hey, I found your panties! I'm good.
马修 你愿意取莉莉\n做为你今生今世的妻子 照顾她
Marshall, do you take Lily to be your wife\nto have and to hold from this day forward?
- 不行 无论贫穷或是富裕\n- 念慢一点 听不清了   我愿意
- Slow down. - I can't. From this day forward so as long as you both shall live? I do.
莉莉 你愿意嫁马修作你的丈夫支持他\n扶持他 无论贫穷或是富裕
Lily, do you promise to take Marshall to\nbe your husband to have and to hold... live?
是的  我愿意
I do.
好的 我以法院门口街道上\n那个脏脏的巴基斯坦人
Okay, then, by the power invested in me by\n the very bitter old Pakistani man
授予我的权力 我现在宣布\n你们成为丈夫和妻子 你可以亲新娘了
who works down at the courthouse on Lafayette Street, I now pronounce you man and wife. You may kiss the bride.
- 你抽烟啦\n- 没有
- Do you smoke?\n- No.
婚姻中的第一个诺言\n来得还真是快啊
Wow. First lie of marriage.\nThat was fast.
当我们回到里面举行第二个婚礼的时候\n很多事情都出了状况 但是不要紧
After that, we all went back inside for the second wedding. And yes, a lot of things did go wrong, but it didn't matter
因为当我们多年后再回首这一天 \n我们只会记得在户外
because when I look back on that day, what I remember is the first wedding;
温馨的那第一个婚礼\n只有好朋友 还有吉它的陪伴
the intimate outdoor ceremony with just close friends and an acoustic guitar.
- 你怎么样 \n- 很累 我今天结了两次婚
How do you feel? Tired. I got\n married twice today.
那么结婚以后的\n第一次你想在哪里"做"
So where do you want to do it for\nthe first time as a married couple,
旅店的客房还是在厕所
nice hotel room or a\nreception hall bathroom?
你觉得呢  当然是厕所
What do you think? Bathroom, of course.
不要吧
Please don't.
抱歉 泰德
- Sorry, Ted.\n- Sorry, Ted.